Guide to the Cornwall Politics Collection 1776-1989 MS 026 MS 026 MS 026
Cornwall Historical Society
Cornwall Politics Collection
1776-1989
Cornwall Historical Society
Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
MS 026
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
This collection contains items relating to Cornwall’s political history.
Provenance
While the majority of papers found in this collection were gathered by Starr, his collection was continued following his death by subsequent historians, such as Emily E. Marsh and Michael Gannett.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
This collection relates to the political history of Cornwall, CT during the period from 1776-1989.
Scope and Content Note
The majority of items in this collection are ballots and tickets for local, state, and national elections during the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. The majority of items were collected by town historian E.C. Starr, and papers relating to politicians reflect his interest in prominent men with ties to Cornwall. Records related to specific issues, censuses, and Cornwall voters are also included in this collection. While the majority of papers found in this collection were gathered by Starr, his collection was continued following his death by subsequent historians, such as Emily E. Marsh and Michael Gannett.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in series by the scope of the election then chronologically within series alphabetically by party and then chronologically.
The files are grouped into 6 series:
Local Elections
State and National Elections
Censuses and Miscellaneous Political Materials
Publications
Political Figures
Miscellaneous
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Politics.; Cornwall (Conn.); Pamphlets; Articles; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
- Local Elections
  - Local ballots, 20-Mar-1944; , undated (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Democratic ballots for justice of the peace, 8-Mar-1908 (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
  - Democratic ticket for local offices, 20-Feb-1909; , undated (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
  - Democratic ticket for representatives and justice of the peace, 1900-1904 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Prohibition Party ballots for justice of the peace, 1894-1896; , undated (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
  - Prohibition Party tickets for local offices, 1889-1895; , undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Republican ballots for justice of the peace, 1894-1898 (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
  - Ballot for Republican school visitors, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Republican ticket for local offices, 1878-1909; , undated (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
  - Republican ticket for representatives and justices of the peace, 1900-1906; , undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Union Republican Party ticket for local offices, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Assorted “Yes” and “No” ballots, undated (Box 1, Folder 30-35)
- State and National Elections
  - Ballots for national and state offices, 1914-1936; , undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ballot for state offices, 1910-1944; , undated (Box 1, Folder 37-47)
  - Ballot for J. Beers and S. Reed as representatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Democratic ballot for representatives, 1894-1896; , undated (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
  - Democratic ballot for school committee, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Democratic ticket for Hancock and English, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Democratic tickets for national and state offices, 1864-1908; , undated (Box 1, Folder 53-65)
  - Democratic and Liberal Party ticket for Greeley and Brown, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - National Democratic Party for national and state offices, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Prohibition Party ballots for representatives, 1894-1898; , undated (Box 1, Folder 68-70)
  - Prohibition Party tickets for national and state offices, 1892-1908; , undated (Box 1, Folder 71-76)
  - Republican ticket for Lincoln and Johnson, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Ticket for “McClellan and the Union!!”, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Republican ballots for representatives, 1894-1898; , undated (Box 1, Folder 79-81)
  - Republican ballot for school committee, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Republican tickets for national and state offices, 1892-1908; , undated (Box 1, Folder 83-92)
  - Union Republican Party ticket for state senators, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Whig State Party ticket for state offices, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Results of vote counters in state election, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Censuses and miscellaneous political materials
  - Connecticut census form for Cornwall, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Certificate showing John Sedgwick’s record as Cornwall representative, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notice for town meeting to discuss the sale of Conn. Western Reserve, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Certificates showing Samuel Wadsworth’s record as Cornwall representative, 1800-1801 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Certificate showing Benjamin Gold’s record as Cornwall representative, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “The Sixth of August” booklet warning of the Jacobin danger to Conn., 1806 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Certificate showing Oliver Burnham’s record as Cornwall representative, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Legislative roll and lodgings, 1831-1832 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Proposal for amendment to state constitution, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - List of Cornwall voters, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Petition by Cornwall Whig Party for reappointment of Whig judge Philo Kellogg, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Protest against town order to remove a fence sent to Cornwall selectmen, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Receipts of Oliver Burnham for having paid annual taxes, 1853-1858 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Account of paupers and road construction, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Results of vote counters in local election, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Payment notice for annual town taxes, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Certified return of ballots form, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Blank tax list, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - List of Democratic voters in Cornwall, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - List of votes tallied, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Typed page regarding child welfare bills, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Letter sent to Republican voters from Cornwall Republican Town Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Letter sent to Democratic voters from Cornwall Democratic Town Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Packet sent to voters by Cornwall Republican Town Committee, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Agreement by citizens to buy street lamps for Cornwall Village, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Blank questionnaire concerning opposition to American imperialism, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - List of Republican voters, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Order of Election Day religious exercises, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Results of vote taken on amendment concerning voting districts, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Results of vote taken on amendment concerning office plurality, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Results of vote taken on issue of license requirement, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - “Yes” ballot regarding the payment of Conn. General Assembly members, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - “Yes” ballot concerning elections of selectmen and local police, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Publications
  - “Revenue for Porto Rico and the Philippines,” by Chester I. Long, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Republican presidential booklet, with speeches and party platform, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper clipping of Conn. census results, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Items relating to the 1901 Constitutional Convention (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - “The Connecticut Oligarchy,” by “Justice", 1902 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Booklet on Conn. Constitutional Convention, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - “Thomas Hooker: The First American Democrat,” by Walter Seth Logan, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - “The Parting of the Ways,” about Parker-Roosevelt election, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - “Governor’s Message to the General Assembly", 1905 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - “The Limitation of Armaments,” by Edwin D. Mead, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - “Why Congressman E.J. Hill Should Represent Connecticut in the U.S. Senate", 1908 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - “McClean vs. Buckley: Connecticut’s Opportunity!”, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Newspaper clipping about Cornwall electoral results, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - “Eternal Vigilance is the Price of Freedom,” pamphlet for William Jennings Bryan for president, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - “Expansion Has Been from the Earliest Day the Policy of Our Country,” by Albert H. Walker, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - “Interview with Professor Willard c. Fisher, “ about Republican politics, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - “To American Clergy,” by the American Party, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - “Sound Money—Sound Business,” by Thomas Hitchcock, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - “The One Vote That Elected A President,” by William George Jordan, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - “The Prohibitory Law of 1855,” by Rev. T.A. Gordon, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - “What Patriotism Demands: An American Catholic’s View,” by J.L. Spaulding, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Political Figures
  - Pledge by senatorial nominee Jerome Alexander to constituents, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Anniversary cards sent to Mr. and Mrs. Beauty from the White House, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Newspaper stories in tribute of Cornwall first selectman Clarence L. Blake, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Clarence L. Blake obituary, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence with E.C. Starr regarding former House Speaker John C. Lewis, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 61-63)
  - Newspaper articles about Matthew Lyon, 1858-1900 (Box 2, Folder 64-67)
  - Correspondence between E.C. Starr and Hart Talcott, regarding Matthew Lyon, 1903-1912 (Box 2, Folder 68-69)
  - Images of Hart Talcott, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr by Talcott, regarding his background, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr by State Treasurer Edward S. Roberts, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Newspaper clipping about Edward S. Roberts, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Miscellaneous
  - Berkshire County, Massachusetts Democratic ticket, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)